

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





K Amarender Reddy () Featured

Accomplished, ambitious and dedicated technocrat, targeting assignments in Teamcenter Administration,

Implementation and Support Analyst with a leading organization of high repute

Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical and Electronics

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Engineering]

Current Designation: Analyst
Current Company: Diebold Nixdorf

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: INDIA

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Tech Support Engnr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: teamcenter unified, product life cycle management, performance monitoring, teamcenter enterprise, fms setup, bmide data modelling, cad integrations, c++, structure manager, sql, teamcenter administration, Teamcenter lmplementation, NX.Workflow

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills

Summary

Siemens PLMTeamcenter Solutions Delivery professional offering over 6 years of IT experience in Product Lifecycle Management for Security and Banking Industry

Hands-on experience in Infrastructure Set-up, Administration, CAD Tools Integration, BMIDE Deployment, Patching & Upgradation and Customization

Possess strong knowledge of Teamcenter Architecture and Infrastructure & Environment

Administered the complete functional testing of Teamcenter Tools which involves Performance Testing and User Acceptance Testing

Extensive knowledge in implementation, configuration, testing, administration and support of Teamcenter V11.xV10.xTCE9.0 MP03 application

Capable in supporting infrastructure like Storage, Active Directory, Network, Firewall & Citrix

Work Experience

Diebold Nixdorf as Analyst Apr 2014 to Till Date

An IT professional with over 6 years of experience in Siemens PLMTeamcenter Solutions Delivery ? Robust experience in Infrastructure Set-up, Administration, CAD Tools Integration, BMDE Deployment, Customization, Patching & Upgrade

- ? Possess strong knowledge of Teamcenter Architecture and Infrastructure & Environment
- ? Extensive knowledge in implementation, configuration, testing, administration and support of Teamcenter V12/V11.x/V10.x,TCE9.0 MP03 application
- ? Capable in supporting infrastructure like Storage, Active Directory, Network, Firewall & Citrix
- ? Hands-on in Cutting Edge Technologies like Teamcenter Utilities and TC integration with NX & AWC
- ? Successfully examined & resolved Teamcenter user issues and customer queries through L1, L2, and L3 Tickets by providing support & solutions in tools like HP-SM, SM9 and Smax
- ? Rich exposure of Operating Systems like Linux Open SUSE and Windows 2008/12 Server
- ? Proven skills in Programming & Scripting Languages like C++,HTML, SQL, Shell, Bash, Python, PowerShell
- ? Skilled in analysing business/functional requirements and applying system business logic to solve complex problems
- ? Expertise in managing complete project management activities and ensuring timely deliveries as per the quality standards
- ? A quick learner, team player having recommendable analytical skills with the capability to work under pressure with limited budgets and meet deadlines
- Diebold Nixdorf Pvt Ltd as Analyst Apr 2014 to Jul 2020

Siemens PLMTeamcenter Solutions Delivery professional offering over 6 years of experience in Product Lifecycle Management for Security and Banking Industry

Hands-on experience in Infrastructure Set-up, Administration, CAD Tools Integration, BMIDE Deployment,

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. Patching & ∪pgradation and ∪ustomization

Possess strong knowledge of Teamcenter Architecture and Infrastructure & Environment

Administered the complete functional testing of Teamcenter Tools which involves Performance Testing and User Acceptance Testing

Extensive knowledge in implementation, configuration, testing, administration and support of Teamcenter

V11.xV10.x,TCE9.0 MP03 application

Capable in supporting infrastructure like Storage, Active Directory, Network, Firewall & Citrix

Managed new installation, software upgradation and software patch installation

Hands-on knowledge of working in:

o FMS Cache Server and Volume server configuration

o Load Balancing for Teamcenter

oTeamcenter Security Services with Kerberos

oDispatcher server setup and custom translators

Good working knowledge of various Teamcenter Modules like Organization, Access manager, Structure Manager.

Diebold Nixdorf India Pvt. Ltd as Analyst (Teamcenter Administrator)

Apr 2014 to Jul 2020

Growth Path:

Apr'14 to May15 - Trainee Analyst

Jun'15 to May'18 - Junior Analyst

Jun'18 to Jul'20 - Analyst

Key Results Areas:

Rendered unified operational support & maintenance for Teamcenter Enterprise/Teamcenter Unified

Understood, analysed and implemented the business requirements by studying information needs

Managed Teamcenter infrastructure, installation, administration and configuration

o TcUA-11.5, 10.1

o TcE - 9.0 MP03 DN Package 9.36

Executed various activities like:

o Set-up of Teamcenter 2T and 4T for different locations

o Set-up of Teamcenter FSC Server and Teamcenter Enterprise Workgroup server at various worldwide locationso

License Server, Workgroups, FSC Servers, Corporate and Webserver

o Citrix Environment, DFS and Firewall

o User accounts, local TC client in User Machines and supported end users by resolving their issues

o Completed DR Setup

o Conducted patching and upgrade from 10.1 to 11.5

Managed and monitored multiple Teamcenter server environments, configurations and changes

Administered dispatcher server setup for custom translations

Worked on various Teamcenter modules like BMDE, Workflow, Organization, Query Builder and Access Manager

Addressed custom Queries in Query Builder and defined custom workflows

Performed BMDE configuration and data modelling

Installed local volumes in different sites to improve the performance of Teamcenter and CAD tools operations

Acquired Hands on understanding of Active Workspace Components

Wrote & improved the Shell Scripts as per the business requirement

Supervised newly set-up servers and services for performance and scalability

Continuously monitored Teamcenter Environments, Services in SCOM and Custom Alerts.

Collaborated with Siemens for vetting custom solutions and managing IR and ER requests

Developed training material and other Teamcenter documentation for building the Knowledge Database

Conducted Unit testing and Integration testing of the project/enhancements

Assisted the team members on various activity progress

Achievements:

Conferred with monthly award (Pat on the Back) for rendering the admin. support to team in 2018

Supported in the Teamcenter UA Upgrade Project TC 10 to TC11

Diebold Nixdorf as Analyst

Apr 2014 to Jul 2020

Siemens PLMTeamcenter Solutions Delivery professional offering over 6 years of experience in Product Lifecycle Management for Security and Banking Industry

Hands-on experience in Infrastructure Set-up, Administration, CAD Tools Integration, BMDE Deployment, Patching & Upgradation and Customization

Possess strong knowledge of Teamcenter Architecture and Infrastructure & Environment

Capable in supporting infrastructure like Storage, Active Directory, Network, Firewall & Citrix

Administered the complete functional testing of Teamcenter Tools which involves Performance Testing and User Acceptance Testing

Extensive knowledge in implementation, configuration, testing, administration and support of Teamcenter V11.xV10.xTCE9.0 MP03 application

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical and Electronics Engineering) from Geethanjali College of Engineering (Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University) in 2012

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Linux System Administration certificate

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C++, SQL,BMIDE Data Modelling,Teamcenter		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Teamcenter Unified			
TEAMCENTER			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary
Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.